先生，多尔达山的人来了
Sir, the people from Doordarshan are here
他们希望你对预算做出回应
They want your reaction on the budget
- 早上好，先生-早上好
- Good morning, sir - Good morning
- 你想要回应，对吗?-是的，先生
- You want a reaction, right? - Yes, sir
当然可以，但是
Sure, I'll give it But
首先，我们去外面
first, let's go outside
今天天气很好
The weather is great today
- 来吧-请
- Come - Please
检查，一，二，三，听得到吗？
Check, one, two, three Am I audible?
能录到SBI作为背景，对吗？
SBI is visible in the background, right?
好吧，我们开始吧
Okay then Let's start
先生，关于突袭的传闻是真的吗？
Sir, this talk about a raid, is it true?
如果我说是，你会就这个问题，而不是问预算了对吧？
If I say yes, will you interview me on that or on the budget?
不会的，先生，采访的内容只有预算
No, sir The interview will only be on the budget
然后放松，深呼吸
Then relax and take a deep breath
风将改变方向
The wind is going to change direction
毫无疑问，这是一个很好的预算
No doubt, it's a great budget
政府正在倾听市场的声音
The government is listening to the market
记住我的话
'And mark my words'
自由化刚起步，这只是个开始
'Liberalisation is just the start It's just a beginning'
现在，印度也将崛起
'Now, India will rise too'
骄傲地站着
'And stand proudly'
与世界大国平起平坐
'at par with the world'
人们总是向我寻求投资方面的建议
'People always ask me for tips on investment'
虽然我从不免费提供信息
'Though I never give out a tip for free'
不过因为今天市场开盘，我会给你一个好消息
'but because the market has opened today, I'll give you an auspicious tip'
在印度投资
'Invest in India'
把钱押在印度身上，因为印度将再创新高
'Put your money on India Because India is going to scale new heights'
[记者]“先生，你让股市大涨”
[Reporter] 'Sir, you have brought about a momentous rise in the stock market'
你认为在预算之后股价会暴涨吗
'Do you think it will explode after the budget?'
听着，我不抽烟
'Look, I don't smoke'
“   但我总是随身带着打火机”
'But I always carry a lighter in my pocket'
就是为了引起爆炸
'Just to cause an explosion'
先生们
Gentlemen
Sensex 指数已经超过了3000点
- The Sensex has crossed 3000 points -[applauds]
让我说一下我个人对这件事的看法
Let Let me tell you what I think about this personally
根据我的经验
According to my experience
这样的繁荣是高度投机性的
a boom like this is highly speculative
因此，我建议机构
So, I would advise institutions
认真思考
to seriously think
现在就卖掉
of selling right now
我相信你们大多数人都会同意，现在是正确的时机
I'm sure most of you would agree that this is the right time
获取利润
to book profits
不仅仅是机构
And not just institutions
我是说股票市场
I would say the stock markets
应该立即采取措施给市场降温
should take immediate steps to cool down the market
已经过热了
Which has been overheated by
对一些股票的过度投机
excessive speculation on some shares
- “先生? ”-“嗯? ”
- 'Sir?' - 'Hmm?'
你真的认为
Do you really think
机构会听你的吗？
the institutions will listen to you?
我是说，据我所知 有传言说
I mean, from what I hear There are rumours
他们只听股票经纪人和市场人士的话
that they only listen to the stockbrokers and market players
股票经纪人？
Stockbroker?
是的，先生，股票经纪人，确切地说，只有一个人
Yes, sir Stockbroker, to be precise just one person
独一无二的大公牛
One and only, The Big Bull
SEBI（印度证券交易委员会）对此做了什么？
And what is SEBI doing about it?
SEBI能做什么，先生？
What can SEBI do, sir?
他们只是谣言
They are just rumours
没有事实和证据，我们能做什么？
What can we do without facts and proofs?
SEBI 有什么权力？
What power does SEBI have?
我们只是一个非执法机构，你知道的
We're just a non-statutory body You know that
但是先生
But sir
印度储备银行有能力
RBI has powers
虽然你不需要按照书本进行调查
Though you need not investigate necessarily by the books
不管怎么说，现在谁负责保管这些账簿，先生? 没有人
Anyway, who maintains the books these days, sir? Nobody
再见
See you
早上好，先生
Good morning, Sir
这边请
This way please
啊！
Ah!
我们被安排在同一班飞机上，是吗? 很好
So, they put us all on the same flight, huh? Thats good
刚才的演讲真是精彩
That was quite a speech out there
哦！
Oh!
你一定不喜欢
You mustn't have liked it
毕竟，你是我们最初的大公牛
After all, you are our original Big Bull
我从公牛的角度观察这次牛市
I am observing this bull run from a bull's perspective
市场相信政府的经济自由化政策
The market believes in the government's economic liberalisation policies
它只是证明了这点
It just demonstrates that
这种牛市行情是自发的
This bull run is spontaneous
现在，我们不应该做任何扰乱市场的事情
Right now, we shouldn't do anything that can disturb the market
[ Pherwani ]“而且  你知道我一生都在这个市场上”
[Pherwani] 'And you know I have been in this market all my life'
我从未见过央行在牛市期间介入
I've never seen the central bank stepping in during a bull run
我部分同意你的意见
I partially agree with you
但只有当资金流向生产部门时，这种情况才会发生
But this can only happen when the money goes to the productive sector
由于目前存在大量投机活动，所有资金都被抽走了
[Venkitarajan ] 'With the current amount of speculation, all the money is being sucked out of there'
因此，央行介入并进行调查是完全合理的
So, it makes perfect sense for the central bank to step in and make enquiries
这也是为了国家的利益
This too is for the good of the nation
- 对不起，先生-什么事？
-[Woman] 'Excuse me, sir' - Yeah?
我想你坐在我的座位上了
'I think you're in my seat'
真的吗? 我 我很抱歉
Really? I I'm sorry
- 我很抱歉-没关系
- I'm so sorry - 'That's okay'
嘿! 八木! 谢谢你能来，很高兴见到你
Hey! Tyagu! Thanks for coming Great to see you
我在停车场没看见一辆雷克萨斯
I didn't see a Lexus in the parking lot
我以为你会邀请所有人
I thought you would have invited everyone
是的，但显然他很忙
I did But apparently, he's busy
阿什温本该来的，但我也没看到他
Ashwin was supposed to come, but I don't see him either
- 晚上好-晚上好，先生们，晚上好
- Good evening - Good evening, gentlemen Good evening
哦！
Oh!
那么，你在玩哪些股票呢? 或者我该说，拉皮条？
So, which stocks are you playing with? Or shall I say, hustling?
情报
Tip
市场上只有两颗宝石
There are only two gems in the market
Polo 和 ACC
Polo and ACC
让我猜猜，马赫什瓦里先生
And let me guess, Mr Maheshwari
你两样都缺，对吧？
You are short on both, right?
我不知道还有什么别的办法
I don't see any other way
Polo 的市盈率为70，ACC 为85
Polo has a P/E of 70 and ACC, 85
我们应该以40的市盈率卖出一只股票
At a P/E of 40, we should sell a stock
我不知道为什么会有人对这些东西这么感兴趣
I have no idea why anybody would be long on those
我知道，它们的价格确实过高
They are truly overpriced, I believe
高市盈率的股票会比低市盈率的股票赚更多的钱
A high P/E scrip will earn you more money than a low P/E scrip
当然，按照哈尔沙德的说法
According to Harshad, of course
也就是说，你的理论已经过时了
Which means, R K, your theory is obsolete
哦，是的
Oh, yes
忘了他吧，他说的都是废话
Forget him He talks rubbish
他的话甚至能使聋子的耳朵流血
He can even make a deaf man's ears bleed
他认为自己是市场上的明星
He thinks he's the rockstar of the market
他带着一个保镖到处走，我的朋友
He walks around with a bodyguard, my friend
忘掉一个摇滚明星吧，他认为自己不亚于巴克强
Forget a rockstar, he thinks he is no less than Bachchan
似乎每个人都在想念哈沙德
'Seems like everybody is missing Harshad'
他似乎是聚会上的热门话题
He seems to be the hot topic of the party
事实上，我们很想你
Actually, we were missing you
我们只是在讨论
We were just discussing
哈沙德的股票市场理论
Harshad's stock market theories
什么理论？
What theories?
每天早上他都会编造一个新的理论
Every morning he makes up a new theory
从媒体到市场，把它传播给每一个人
and feeds it to everyone from the media to the market
通过非法资金推高市场
and pushes the market up by channelizing illegal funds
对
Right
但他会倒下
But he will fall
他和市场都会下跌
Both he and the market, will fall
这种情况不能持续下去
This can't be sustained
甚至印度央行行长前几天也在谈论这个问题
Even the RBI governor was talking about it the other day
你看，在他说完之后
And see After he spoke about it
市场在两天内下跌了400点？
the market did fall by 400 points in two days?
但这还不够，还需要进一步修正
But not enough, it needs to correct more
我们过去六个月一直持有空头头寸
Look, we have been holding our short positions for the past six months
如果这种牛市再持续一个月
If this bull run continues for one more month
我们将一无所有
we'll be left with nothing
我们每天都面临亏损
We're facing losses daily
再也承受不起了
We can't take it anymore
如果再这样下去
If this goes on any longer
我们都得去红灯区站街
we'll have to sell ourselves in the red light district
如果你在那接不到客，你可以来这里
If you don't get a place there you can come here
索纳加奇
to Sonagacchi
但是，严肃地说，你应该和印度储备银行行长谈谈
But hey listen, on a serious note, you must talk to the RBI governor
他们应该试着弄清楚到底发生了什么
They should try to find out what's going on
哈尔沙德的所有消息来源都令人怀疑
All of Harshad's sources are dubious
他是个该死的街头小贩
He's a bloody street-seller
先生，我很高兴你对这个市场很感兴趣
Sir, I am glad you are taking an active interest in the market
你的演讲在市场上产生了巨大的影响
Your speech has made a great impact in the market
我知道
Yeah, I know
我们的责任是对中小投资者负责
Our responsibility is towards the small retail investors
他们是最脆弱的
'They are the most vulnerable'
“目前的趋势对他们来说是一种误导”
'The present trends are misleading for them'
当泡沫破灭的时候
When the bubble bursts
街上会血流成河
there will be blood on the streets
没错
True
我不知道发生了什么事
I've no idea what's going on
一方面是货币市场的这些非法活动
On one hand, these illegal activities in the money market
另一方面，又是股票市场的繁荣
and on the other, the stock market boom
[ Venkitarajan ]“这个系统里没有钱”
[Venkitarajan ] 'There is no money in the system'
然而，哈尔沙德却可以继续购买价值数亿元的股票
And yet, Harshad continues to buy shares worth crores
告诉我
Tell me
哈萨德的资金来源是什么？
What are Harshad's sources of funds?
有传言说可能是任何东西
Rumour says it could be anything
走私犯，电影明星，毒枭，黑社会
'Smugglers, film stars, drug lords, underworld'
我觉得这些都不是
I doubt it's any of that
几天前，所得税部门在哈沙德的住处进行了一起突击检查
A few days back, there was an income tax raid at Harshad's place
如果你愿意，可以和他们谈谈
You can speak to them if you want
他们可能有一些发现
They may have found something
先生，他什么都知道
Sir, he knew everything
所有的一切，什么时间，什么地点
Everything When, where, how
我们经过哪条路线
Which route we were coming by
我的意思是，他甚至知道我们会路过几个寺庙
I mean, he also knew how many potholes we would cross
他还为我们准备了南印度小吃
He had arranged South-Indian snacks for us
显然，我们不会找到任何文件
Obviously, we weren't going to find any documents
在我们到达之前，他已经把所有的东西都藏起来了
He had hidden everything before we reached
当我们的队伍到高摩资本时
And when our team reached Growmore
他们被告知所有的资料都在电脑里
they were told that all the documents are in the computer
但是没有人知道密码
But nobody knew the password
电脑操作员正在休假
And the computer operator was on leave
他的父亲恰巧在那天去世
His father conveniently died the same day
所以他回老家了
So he had gone to his village
从那以后就再也没回过孟买
And hasn't come back to Bombay ever since
我觉得他不会回来了
I don't think he's coming back
没错，先生
Exactly, sir
所以我们从哥印拜陀请来了一位专家来破解电脑
That's why, we've called in an expert from Coimbatore to crack it
但是他说破解需要很长的时间
But he's saying that it will take some more time
一定有办法找到他的资金来源
There must be some way to find the source of his funds
我是说任何物证或者……
I mean, any physical evidence or
肯定有什么蛛丝马迹
There must be something?
现在还没有，先生
Nothing as of now, sir
但是他的 SBI 帐户
But his SBI account
有很多资金活动
There's a lot of activity in that
大量的资金正在流入
A lot of money is coming in
所以，如果我们能追踪这笔钱，我想我们就能找到真正的来源
So, if we can trail the money, I think we can find the real source
好吧
Alright
- 定期向我汇报最新情况-好的先生
- Keep me regularly updated on this - Sure, sir
即使这些信息看起来毫无用处
Even if the information seems useless
- 我还是要定期汇报-是的先生
- I still want a regular update - Yes, sir
有消息通知我
Keep me posted
你要走了吗，先生？
Sir Are you leaving, sir?
- 发生什么事了? 有什么急事吗?-先生
- What happened? Anything urgent? - Sir, uh
-把包放在车里-好的先生
- Uh Leave the bag in the car - Yes, sir
- 什么事? 有什么急事吗?-先生，你曾要求SBI
- Yeah What is it? Anything urgent? - Sir, you had asked SBI Bombay
发送哈尔沙德 · 梅塔往来账户的详细信息
main branch to send the details of Harshad Mehta's current account
先生我们刚收到了资金流水
Sir, we just got the statement
- 然后呢?-先生
- And? - Sir
我想你应该亲自去看看，先生
I think you should see it yourself, sir
- 天哪! 好吧-先生 谢谢你先生
- Oh, God! Okay - Sir Thank you, sir
这令人吃惊
This is startling
一个人的活期账户竟然有这么大金额的流水？
So much movement in an individual's current account?
先生，3、4亿就像零钱
Sir, 30 to 40 crores are like loose change
所有转帐项目都是以亿为卢比计算的
All transfer entries are in crores
先生，3月9日余额是 这个，18.6亿卢比
Sir, 9th March balance was This one, sir 186 crores
戈伊波利亚知道吗？
Goiporia knows?
先生，他是 SBI 的主席
[Ghosh] 'Sir, he's the chairman of SBI'
他明天就会接受审查
He's getting the vouchers scrutinised tomorrow
到时候这些资金
Then, these funds
从哪来到哪去
from where they're coming, and where they're going
我们就都知道了
we'll know everything
听着，阿米塔夫
Listen Listen, Amitav
我们的官员也应该仔细检查这些条目
Our officers should also scrutinize these entries
- 并行处理，这是头等大事-先生
- Do this parallelly This is top priority - Sir
我想和财政部长分享这一声明
I'd like to share this statement with the finance minister
其次
Secondly
给 Goiporia 发个短信
Send a note to Goiporia
让他把哈沙德的账户置于持续监控之下
Tell him to put Harshad's account under constant monitoring
你好，你好吗，阿姆里克兄弟？
Hello, how are you, Amrik brother?
一切都好吗？
All okay?
我不是告诉过你Polo会很棒吗？
Didn't I tell you that Polo is going to rock?
我希望你父亲现在开心了？
I hope your father is happy now?
他很开心，哈沙德，但就像我说的，他有点守旧
He's happy, Harshad Bhai But like I said, he's a little old school
他看到这样的暴涨很担心
He's worried that Seeing such a rise
投资者不会问问题吗？
won't investors start asking questions?
兄弟，人们只有在面临损失时才会质疑
Bhai, People only question when they face losses
当他们赚钱的时候，没有人会问任何问题
Nobody asks anything when they are making profits
人们甚至还没有看到真正的增长
And people haven't even seen the real rise yet
让你爸爸放松点
Ask your father to relax
好吧，听着，我下周会去德里
Okay, listen I'll be in Delhi, next week
我们见面后再聊吧？
Let's chat more once we meet?
当然，我们会等你的
Sure, we'll be waiting
好的，再联系
Okay, Jai Shree Kri Sat Sri Akaal
阿卡尔先生，再联系
Sat Sri Akaal, talk to you soon
来吧
Come on
游泳时不要带浮子，快点！
Swim without the floater Come on!
喂？
Hello?
先生？
Sir?
先生，他说是很重要的事
Sir, he says it's important
真烦人！
So annoying!
- 喂?-喂，先生，我是西塔拉曼
- Hello? - Hello, sir It's Sitaraman
告诉我，西塔的拉曼! 什么风把你吹来了？
Tell me, Sita's Raman! To what do I owe this pleasure?
[西塔拉曼]“先生  很抱歉打扰你”
[Sitaraman] 'Sir Sorry to disturb you'
但是很紧急，先生，有个问题
But it's urgent, sir There's a problem
担心能给你带来收入吗？
Do you get a salary for worrying or doing your job?
你总是忧心忡忡
You're always high on worry
[西塔拉曼]“先生，我们有理由担心”
[Sitaraman] 'Sir, there's a reason to worry'
戈伊波利亚先生要你发表声明
Goiporia sir has called for your statements
(西塔拉曼)“我听说这个命令直接来自印度储备银行”
[Sitaraman] 'I heard that the order came directly from RBI'
“先生，如果他们知道了怎么办? 我很担心，先生”
'Sir, what if they get to know? I'm feeling very worried, sir'
请尽快结清我们所有的帐目
Please settle all our accounts as soon as possible Please
“如果他们知道  ”
'If they come to know'
先生，我觉得很害怕，先生
Sir I'm feeling very afraid, sir
- 嘿，爸爸!-[西塔拉曼]‘喂，先生? ’
- Hey, Pappa! -[Sitaraman] 'Hello, sir?'
- 你看到了吗? 我刚游了四圈-你好，先生
- Did you see? I just swam four laps -[Sitaraman] 'Hello, sir?'
你永远看不到眼前的事
You never see what's in front of you
算了吧
Forget it
你为什么不回答？
Why don't you answer?
(哈沙德)“我是这个行业的新手吗? ”
[Harshad] 'Am I new to this business?'
这是我第一次让你造假吗？
Is this the first time I'm asking you for a roll-over?
这怎么可能造的了呢，先生？
How can it be rolled over, sir?
这一次，非常困难
This time, it's very difficult
先生，一只鹰的眼睛盯着你呢，每一页都被仔细检查过了
A hawk's eye is on your account, sir Every page is being scrutinised
- 先生-我知道明天就过期了
- And sir - I know, tomorrow is the expiry date
我就是这个意思，先生，明天就是到期日
That's what I'm saying, sir Tomorrow is the expiry date
17亿卢比
It's an entry of 170 crores
你还没给我 BRs 呢
You haven't even given me the BRs
我很害怕，先生
I'm very scared, sir
如果有人知道了怎么办? 一想到这个我就烧心
What if someone comes to know? I'm getting heartburn just thinking of it
那你就打个嗝，西塔拉曼小姐
Then burp and move on, Sitaraman ji
先生，我不在乎，我现在就要17亿卢比，就这样
Sir, I don't care I want 170 crores right now That's it
- 17亿卢比?-是的，先生
- 170 crores? - Yes, sir
- 一天之内?-是的，先生
- In one day? - Yes, sir
- 你脑子有问题吗?-有……
- Has your brain curdled? - Ye
- 没有，先生-布尚，冷静点
- No, sir - Bhushan, calm down
我怎样才能保持冷静？
How can I keep calm?
[ Bhushan ]“如果我们把17亿从市场上撤出来，那么我们的处境将会很糟糕”
[Bhushan] 'If we pull it out from the market then we'll be in deep shit'
我们股价会跌落谷底，兄弟！
Our a**e will look like a cave, brother!
[ Bhushan ]“现在不是给钱的时候，你很清楚这一点”
[Bhushan] 'This is not the time to dole money out, you know it well'
因为这个那次讲话，Sensex 指数已经下跌了400点
Sensex has dropped by 400 points because of this Venkitarajan
已经从3500跌到3100
It has gone from 3500 to 3100
兄弟，为这17亿想点别的计划，就这样
Brother, come up with some other plan for this 170 crores, that's it
先生，17亿可能不算什么
Sir, the 170 crores is nothing
但是如果他们把这17亿引向那50亿怎么办？
What if this 170 crores leads them to those 500 crores?
-先生，请理解-我知道
- Sir Sir, please try to under - I know
我知道是我去年拿的，冷静点
I know I took it last year Calm down
我会给你17亿卢比
You will get your 170 crores
但是50亿卢比，必须从账簿中删除
But the 500 crores, must stay out of the books
- 从账簿里删除?-是的
- Out of the books? - Yes
我去处理 PDO
I will handle the PDO
- 你想给你儿子举行剃头仪式，对吧?-嗯？
- You wanted to hold your son's tonsuring ceremony, right? - Huh?
- 是的-你想去是吗？
- Yes - You wanted to go, right?
你休假了吗？
Did you get leave?
- 是的-太好了，你要去哪里？
- Yes - Great Where are you going?
- 哥印拜陀附近的寺庙 -哇！
- Palani, near Coimbatore - Wow!
所以，坐飞机去吧，你和你的家人
So, go by air You and your family
- 布尚?-嗯？
- Bhushan? - Yes?
“安排他的旅行”
[Harshad] 'Arrange for his travel and stay'
当然可以
Yeah, sure
玩得开心！
Have fun!
嘿，恰万
Hey, Chavan
办公室已经关门了，你现在才吃饭！
The office has closed and you're eating now!
嘿，西塔拉姆，请坐，和我们一起吃
Hey, Sitaram have a seat Come, eat with us
不用了，谢谢，你吃吧，我还有工作要做
No, thanks You go on I have some work
我必须在分类账上登记一笔
I have to make an entry in the ledger
- 好吧我跟你一起去-不
- Okay, I'll come with you - No
你吃吧，我来处理
You please eat I'll manage
- 不，没关系，我跟你一起去 -不，请坐
- No, that's okay I'll come - No, please sit
- 没问题-确定？
- No problem - Sure?
- 当然，坐下吧-好的
- Sure Sit - Okay
谢谢
Thank you
好吧，告诉我
Okay, tell me something
为什么印度储备银行行长
Why is the RBI Governor
像公牛一样挤进股票市场？
shoving his horns into the share market like a bull?
他可以把手伸到任何地方，为什么偏偏要插手我的 SBI 帐户呢？
He can shove them wherever he wants But why is he butting into my SBI account?
他很快就会查到我们的账户
He's only entered the account now Soon he will be up our a**
- 你为什么在家里骂人?-因为这次是认真的
- Why are you cussing at home? - Because this time it is serious
你为钱发疯了
You've gone mad for money
你一直在喊‘钱，钱，钱  ’
You keep chanting 'money, money, money' all the time
什么钱你都赚
If not from here then from there, if not there then elsewhere
你到底要赚多少钱，哈沙德？
How much will you hustle, Harshad?
眼里只有钱，你会毁掉身边的所有人
In trying to save one, you'll break at a hundred more
我警告过你
I had warned you
哈沙德，你已经变得如此强大，以至于现在有大人物在追杀你
Harshad, you've become so big that now, big people are after you
- 你明白吗?-我什么都明白
- Do you get that? - I get everything
你如果真的明白了，那么在一切都太晚之前解决问题
If you get it, then before it's too late, settle everything Bhai
你以为你在挖金矿，但实际上你可能是在自掘坟墓
You think you're digging a gold-mine But it can turn into your grave
你意识到了吗？
Do you realise?
嘿，冷静点
Hey, Shashi Kapoor, calm down
冷静，游戏规则不是这样的
Calm down That's not how it works Wait
这样吧，去会见印度储备银行行长
Do one thing, go meet the RBI governor
和他谈谈
Speak with him
试着读出他在想什么
Try to read what's on his mind
- 就这么简单-简单！
- Simple - Simple!
他会拿着一束花等着欢迎我们，不是吗？
He's just waiting with a bouquet to welcome us, isn't he?
他要是不欢迎我，我会……
If he's not, then we will make him
我会让德里的朋友给他打电话
We'll get friends in Delhi to call him
我要一些薄饼
I'll have some jalebis
听着，先生，相信我
[Harshad] 'Look, sir Believe me'
印度的国内外债务问题
India's foreign and domestic debt problem
只能通过资本市场和直接投资组合来解决
can only be solved by the capital markets and direct portfolio investments
梅塔先生，我听说过你的很多理论
Mr Mehta, I've heard about your multiple theories
但这是极其错误的
But this is exceptionally wrong
大错特错
Incorrect Absolutely incorrect
长期证券可以在国际收支平衡方面创造出来
Longterm securities can be created on the balance of payments front
只有在经济呈指数增长的时候
only when the economy grows exponentially
“或者  ”
[Venkitarajan ] 'Or'
“  当石油进口等耗费巨额外汇的支出减少时”
'when forex-guzzling expenditure like petroleum import is reduced'
- 你明白我的意思吗?-我完全明白你的意思
- You get my point? - I absolutely get your point
但如果你给我两个小时
But if you just give me two hours
我会一点一点向你解释一切
I will explain you everything point by point
[哈沙德]“你看，甚至克里希那穆尔蒂先生也喜欢我的想法”
[Harshad] 'You see even Mr Krishnamurthy liked my ideas'
哦，是的! 他很敬畏你
Oh, yes! He was in awe of you
差点逼我来见你
Almost forced me to meet you
我无法拒绝，毕竟他是计划委员会的成员
I couldn't refuse After all he is a member of the planning commission
你真是太好了，先生
[Harshad] 'That's really kind of you, sir'
我相信我能百分之百地说服你
I am sure that I can convince you a 100 percent
给我两个小时
Just give me two hours
梅塔先生，我
Mr Mehta, I'd
我愿意给你两个小时听你的观点
love to give you two hours to listen to you and
然后用十分钟来证明你是错的
ten more minutes to prove you wrong
但老实说
But frankly
我不想浪费你我的时间
I don't want to waste my time or yours
还有别的事吗，梅塔先生？
Is there anything else, Mr Mehta?
我有个请求
I have a request
- 如果你能和 SBI 谈谈-我应该和 SBI 谈什么？
- If you could talk to SBI - What should I talk to SBI about?
现在他们只听你的，不是吗？
They listen only to you these days, don't they?
他们现在和我真的很难相处
And they are really being difficult with me now
因为他们从你的办公室得到了所有的指示
Because they are getting all the instructions from your office
梅塔先生，我开会真的要迟到了
Mr Mehta, I am really getting late for my next meeting
所以，请见谅
So, if you could kindly excuse me
再见
Goodbye
- “先生? ”-“嗯，你说”
- 'Sir?' -[Khemani] 'Yes, tell me'
我们认为这可能是一个常规的计算错误
We thought this might be a regular calculation error
在对账过程中，这种事时有发生
It happens, during the reconciliation
但是，先生，这次不是一个小错误，而是一个大错误
But sir, this time it's not a small error, it looks like a big one
你能详细说明一下吗？
Can you please elaborate?
先生，看看这个
Sir, look at this
我们的账簿显示
Our books show
价值174.4亿卢比的有价证券
securities worth 1744 crores
“等一下  ”
[Khemani] 'Wait a minute'
- 我们的账本上有多少钱?-174.4亿卢比
- How much do our books show? -[Kamat] '1,744 crores'
- 174.4亿卢比?-是的
- 1744 crores? - Yes
然而PDO 发送的 RBI 记录显示
And the RBI statement sent by the PDO
“我们的证券价值只有167亿卢比”
[Kamat] 'those records show that we have securities worth only 1,670 crores'
167亿，所以差了7.4亿卢比
1,670 So, there's a difference of 74 crores
先生，这7.4亿卢比的差额
Sir, this 74 crore difference
我们以为是计算错误，所以检查了帐目
we thought it was a calculation error and checked the accounts
我们一直在想办法对平，但是
We were trying to figure it out, but
但是什么？
But what?
印度储备银行的数字不是167亿卢比
RBI's figure is not 1,670 crores
- 是117亿-117亿
- It's 1,170 crores - 1,170
- 1170?-是的
- 1,170? -[Kamat] 'Yes'
先生，这不是计算错误
Sir, this is not a calculation error
我们的账户里少了57.4亿卢比
574 crores are missing from our accounts
- 什么?-是的，先生
- What? - 'Yes, sir'
但是这个对账单来自于 PDO，不是吗？
But this statement has come from PDO, right?
- 是的-让我看看
-[Kamat] 'Yes' - Show me
167亿，没错啊
1,670 It's written right here
[卡玛特]“先生，仔细看看”
[Kamat] 'Sir, look at it carefully'
“这里‘一’被改写成了‘六’的样子”
'Here 'One' has been overwritten to make it look like a 'Six''
“看”
'See'
西塔拉曼？
Sitaraman?
先生，就是他把文件带来的
Sir, he's the one who brought the files from RBI
五十亿卢比可是一大笔钱
[mumbling] Five hundred crore is a big sum
那么，西塔拉曼是否有银行收据或证券作为抵押呢？
So, does Sitaraman have Bank Receipts or securities against this?
-有没有?-先生
- Yes or no? - 'Sir'
卡玛特？
Kamat?
不确定，先生
Not sure, sir
西塔拉曼从昨天开始休假
Sitaraman is on leave since yesterday
实际上，先生，他休假是因为他儿子的剃发仪式
Actually sir, it's his son's tonsure ceremony
所以，他去了 Palani，靠近哥印拜陀
'So, he's gone to Palani, near Coimbatore'
别跟我说细节
Spare me the details
马上去，检查他的桌子，橱柜，文件 所有的东西
Go immediately Check his desk, cupboards, files everything
如果你必须打开锁，那就撬开，快去！
If you have to break the locks, do it Go!
好的，先生
Okay, sir
用棍子撬开
Hit it with the rod
- 对就像这样 -用力
- Yeah, like that - Hit it
“啊，是的”
[Kamat] 'Ah, yes'
怎么样了？
What happened?
- 有什么发现吗?-没有，先生，还没有
- Did you find anything? - No sir, nothing yet
跟我来
Come with me
领导在吗？
Is sir in?
- 他刚走-他去哪儿了？
- He just left - Where did he go?
楼下，他刚走
Downstairs He just left
先生! 先生! 先生！
Sir! Sir! Sir!
- 西塔拉曼到底在哪儿?-他去村子里了
- Where the hell is Sitaraman? - He's gone to the village
他在休假，我们甚至弄坏了他的储物柜，但是
He's on leave We even broke his locker But nothing
恐怕这是一起诈骗案
I'm afraid, it's a clear case of fraud, sir
淦！
F**k!
有人跟他说过话吗？
Has anyone spoken to him?
- 不-我们先不要惊慌
- No - Let's not panic right now, Khemani
首先，把他带回来，这个西塔拉曼，他在你手下工作，对吧？
First, bring him back This Sitaraman, he works under you, right?
取消他的假期
Cancel his leave
先生，他在 Palani，靠近哥印拜陀
Sir, he's in Palani, near Coimbatore
- 这是他儿子的剃发仪式-Palani 还是 Paris 我不在乎
- It's his son's tonsure - Palani or Paris I don't care
把他带回来，他是你的责任
Bring him back He's your responsibility
我们应该通知主席先生吗？
Should we inform chairman sir?
在那之前我们需要所有其他的细节
We need all the other details before that
先把西塔拉曼带回来，好吗？
First priority is Sitaraman Okay?
快去！
Please leave right now!
喂？
Hello?
谢谢
Ah, thank you
拉詹，我们的安全官员，先生
[Krishnan] 'Rajan Our security officer, sir'
他的团队从昨天开始就在寻找锡塔拉曼，先生
'His team has been looking for Sitaraman since yesterday, sir'
- 你找到他了吗?-没有，先生-没有，先生
- Did you find him? - No, sir - No, sir
不过别担心，先生，穆鲁根大人和我们在一起
But don't worry, sir Lord Murugan is with us
我们去把他堵在寺庙里
Let's do one thing Let's trap him at the temple
先生！
Sir!
先生
S-Sir
你来了，先生！
You came, sir!
我邀请了整个办公室的人
I invited the entire office, sir
但只有你来了，非常感谢，先生
but only you came Thank you so much, sir
我现在是一个人来的
I have come alone, for now
其他人都在孟买等你
Everyone else is waiting for you in Bombay
把盘子放下，跟我来，我需要和你谈谈
Do one thing Leave this here and come with me I need to talk to you
- 现在吗，先生?-是的，快放下，来吧
- Right now, sir? - Yes, keep it Come
快点，来
Keep it Come
带他的家人去旅馆
Take his family to the hotel
- 好的，先生-夫人，我们马上回来
-[Krishnan] 'Okay, sir' -[Kamat] 'Bhabhi ji, we'll be back'
- “来吧，西塔拉曼”-“先生 ”
- 'Come on, Sitaraman' -[Sitaraman] 'Sir'
先生，他们在收拾行李了
Sir, they are packing
为什么，先生？
Packing, sir?
发生什么事了，先生？
What happened, sir?
你大老远跑来
You've come all the way
- 有问题吗?-有问题吗？
- Any problem? - Any problem!?
我是不是被一只疯狗咬了，然后一路跟着你到了这里，一点问题都没有？
Was I bitten by a mad dog, to follow you all the way here, without a problem?
什么问题，先生？
What problem, sir?
五十亿卢比
Five hundred crores
哦，先生，那50亿根本不是问题，先生
Oh Sir, that 500 crore is no problem at all, Sir
我有完整的记录，先生
I have a complete record of it, sir
账目，明细，所有的一切，先生
Accounts, details, everything, sir
事实上，因为我儿子的剃头仪式，我走得很匆忙，所以我忘了
Actually, I left in a hurry because of my son's ceremony So, I forgot
- 我回来后会处理的
- I will manage it once I return -[chair screeching]
- 你忘了?-对不起，先生
- You forgot? - Sorry, sir
你忘了登记50亿! ？
You forgot to account for 500 crores!?
非常抱歉，先生我会处理的，先生
Very sorry, sir I will manage, sir
- 你能处理什么?-我
- What will you manage? - I
什么？
Huh?
我不是那个意思，先生，我说的处理是指……
I didn't mean that, sir By manage, I mean
这……我……
-[chair screeching] - It's I
- 我在休假-休假？
- I was on leave - Leave?
忘了你的假期，好吗？
Forget your leave, okay?
我星期四回去上班，先生
I'll be back on Thursday, sir
我买了从马德拉斯来的机票，和家人一起回去
I have flight tickets from Madras With family
我们一样带你坐飞机回去
We will also take you by flight
和你的家人一起
You and your family
准备好
Get ready
没有，先生
No, sir
我很抱歉
I'm very sorry
但是，我没有SGL，先生
But, I don't have the SGL, sir
坐下
Sit here
坐下！
Sit!
他昨天告诉卡马特，他有 SGL
He told Kamat yesterday that he has the SGL
嗯？
Hmm?
你有还是没有？
Did you or didn't you?
- 是不是你干的? !-是我先生
- Did you or didn't you?! - I did, Sir
- 然后呢?-但是，我真的很害怕，先生
- Then? - But, I was really scared then, sir
-我的家人和我在一起-你的家人现在不在这里
- Also, my family was with me - Your family isn't here right now
说清楚点，你为什么没有 SGL？
Tell me clearly Why don't you have the SGL?
听着，西塔拉曼，我们说的不是500卢比
Look, Sitaraman We're not talking about 500 rupees
我们的帐本上少了50亿卢比
Five hundred crores are missing from our books
你会因此坐牢的
You can go to jail for this
一旦你进了监狱，他们就会把你打得遍体鳞伤
And once you go to jail, they'll beat you black and blue
有BRs，先生
BRs are there, sir
什么？
What?
BRs
说清楚点！
Speak clearly!
有BRs，先生
BRs are there, sir
你有BR吗
[Khemani] 'BRs are there?'
西塔拉曼，你为什么一直不说呢？
Sitaraman, why didn't you say that all this while?
你嘴里塞了什么东西吗？
Have you stuffed something in your mouth?
你应该早点说的
You could've said this earlier
卡玛特？
Kamat?
你马上去他那拿br
You collect all the BRs from him, immediately
- 好的，先生，走吧-BRs 不在我这里，先生
- Right sir Come on - BRs are not with me, sir
我要给你一巴掌！
I'll give you one tight slap!
你嗑药了吗？
Are you on drugs?
他刚刚才说的，是不是？
He just said, didn't he
你刚才说 五秒钟前
You just said five seconds back
你有 BRs
that you have the BRs
你还好吗？
Are you okay? Huh?
西塔拉曼
Sitaraman
你感觉还好吗？
Are you feeling fine?
有BR，先生
BRs are there, sir
但是不在我这里
But they are not with me
在谁那里？
[Sudhakar] 'Whom are they with?'
哈尔沙德 · 梅塔
Harshad Mehta
有些植物需要更多的水，比如那些植物
Some plants need more water Like those ones
去给它们浇水
Go and water them
那儿，就在那儿
There Right there
- 早上好，先生-你好，先生
- Good morning, sir - Hello, sir
哈尔沙德？
Harshad?
是的，先生
Yes, sir
证券应该来自旁遮普国家银行
Securities were supposed to come from PNB
那他们为什么不给呢？
So why didn't they come?
不，那是哈沙德告诉我的
No That's what Harshad had told
-西塔拉曼-去他的西塔拉曼
- to Sitaraman - To hell with Sitaraman
你有和旁遮普国家银行联系过吗？
Did you speak with PNB directly?
- 我们联系了，然后……-然后？
- We spoke to and - And?
先生，钱从来没有到过旁遮普国家银行
Sir, the money never reached PNB
- 那他们为什么要给 ?-从来没到过？
- So, why would they give? - It never reached?
我不明白
I don't understand
事实上，先生
- [Khemani] 'Actually, sir' -[Khemani clears throat]
这些支票是以梅塔先生的名义签发的
The cheques were issued in Mr Mehta's name
[ Khemani ]“他从我们这里拿走了钱，但没有给他们”
[Khemani] 'He took the money from us, but didn't give it to them'
所以，我们没有收到证券
So, we didn't receive the securities
这就是原因，先生
And that's the reason, sir
我们账上缺了50亿卢比
we are short on 500 crore rupees
“我们正在进行内部调查，先生，但是  ”
[Sudhakar] 'We're doing an internal enquiry sir But'
首先我们要从哈尔沙德那里追回钱
the priority is that we should recover the money from Harshad
先生，我想你应该和他谈谈
Sir, I think, you should speak with him
我是说，如果你开口
I mean, if you speak
- 卡玛尼- 一定会给他很大压力
- Khemani - it will build some pressure
卡玛尼，看着我
Khemani, look at me
你以为你在跟谁说话？
Who do you think you're talking to?
- 不，先生，我是说-我看起来像
- No, sir I was saying - Do I look like
一个给你讨债的人吗? 告诉我
a recovery agent to you, Khemani? Tell me
- 不，先生，我想说的是-闭嘴
- No sir, what I meant to say - Shut up, Khemani
我是这个国家最大的银行的主席
I am the chairman of the largest bank in this country
是的，先生
[Khemani] 'Yes, sir'
我直接与政府就财政政策打交道
I deal directly with the government on the finance policy
是的，先生
Yes, sir
我直接与财政部长打交道
[Goiporia] 'I deal directly with the finance minister'
现在，你却让我去对付一个中间人
And today, you are telling me to deal with some middle-man
你他妈吃错药了吗
who has shown you the middle finger?
卡玛尼，这是你造成的，你来处理
Khemani, you created this mess, you handle it
“原因很简单，先生，我已经拿到了BRs”
[Harshad] 'It's simple, sir I took the BRs from Sitaraman'
显然，这样我就可以从 PNB 得到 SGL
Obviously, so that I can get SGL from PNB
- 然后呢?-发生了什么？
- And what happened then? - What happened?
我带着BR回到办公室，但是税局的人来突击检查
I reached office with the BRs but the IT guys did a raid there
他们带来了一支庞大的队伍，办公室现在还封锁着
They came with a huge squad It's all still sealed
情况是这样的，即使我有 BRs，我也做不了什么
Circumstances are such, that though I have BRs, I can't do anything
就算你被突袭了又怎么样？
So what if you've been raided?
SBI 与此有什么关系？
What does SBI have to do with it?
我们必须遵守规则，不是吗？
We have to follow the rules, don't we?
我希望我的账簿是干净的，梅塔先生
I want my books to be clean, Mr Mehta
怎么了? 谁让你送的茶？
What is it? Who called for tea?
先生，我看到客人在这里，所以我想……
[Peon] 'Sir, I saw sir here So, I thought'
放在这儿，伙计
Keep it here, buddy Here
“你们有腰果饼干吗? ”
[Harshad] 'Do you have those cashew cookies?'
有的，先生
[Peon] 'Yes, sir'
-拿过来-马上就来，先生
- Bring those also - 'In a minute, sir'
先生，我对我的账簿了如指掌
Sir, I know my books very well
你知道，在过去的五年里
And you know, in the last five years
SBI 和我一起做了很多生意
SBI and I have done lots of business together
1700亿，这可不是小数目，先生
17,000 crores It's not a small amount, sir
什么？
Huh?
SBI 从中获得了多少利润？
And how much profit did SBI make from it?
至少2亿卢比吧？
At least 200 crores?
现在你突然说我会和你的50亿一起消失？
Now suddenly you're saying that I will disappear with your 500 crores?
别这样，先生，你了解我的，我是个诚实的人
Come on, sir You know me I'm an honest man
我该拿你的诚信怎么办？
What do I do with your honesty?
我可以在我的报告上写: “梅塔先生是一个诚实的人”
Can I write on my statement? 'Mr Mehta is an honest person'
让我们把话说清楚，梅塔先生
Let's make it very clear, Mr Mehta
要么给我 BRs，要么给我证券
Either give me the BRs or the securities
否则，立即返还全部现金
Or else, return the entire amount immediately
好吧，假设我是坏人
Okay, let's say I'm the bad guy
但你是个好人，对吧？
But you're a good man, right?
那就乖乖的
Then be good
给我一个星期，我会解决一切问题
Give me one week I'll settle everything
先生
[Peon] 'Sir'
伙计，SBI今天的茶很苦
Buddy, SBI's tea was very bitter today
让他们加一些糖
Ask them to add some sugar
开车送我回家
Drive me home, buddy
哈尔沙德回家了
'Harshad is home'
“你吃吗，孩子? ”
'Will you eat, son?'
哈尔沙德
Harshad
不要只是静静地坐着，兄弟
Don't just sit silently, Bhai
跟我说说
Talk to me
详细地告诉我
Tell me in detail
我应该告诉你什么？
What should I tell you?
如果我开口，你又会开始教训我
If I say anything, you'll start lecturing me again
你放松点，我正在想办法
You relax I'm figuring it out
兄弟
Look, Bhai
我知道那天我很生气
I know I got very angry the other day
但那不是我的愤怒
But that wasn't my anger
而是我的恐惧
It was my fear
好吧，告诉我，你争取了多少时间？
Okay forget that Tell me how much time have you bought?
一个星期
A week
只有一个星期？
Only a week?
一方面，是税局突袭
On one hand, this IT raid
另一方面，印度储备银行调查
And on the other, that RBI Governor
现在，还有SBI的问题
Now, a new problem with SBI
所有这一切都发生在
And, all of it just when
我们需要钱来维持市场的时候
we need money to keep the market up
运气不好的时候，连猴子都斗不过
When your luck is bad, you can lose a fight even to a monkey
这次不只是一只猴子
It's not just one monkey this time
- 这是一支猴子军队，哈沙德-不
- It's an army of monkeys, Harshad - No
不是猴子，是一群熊
Not the monkeys, it's an army of bears
那些该死的熊在追我
Those bloody bears are after me
不过没关系，我们也一样坚强
But that's okay We are just as strong
像哈努曼一样
Like Hanuman
如果他们放火烧我的尾巴，我就放火烧了他们的王国
If they set fire to my tail, I will set their kingdom ablaze
还没睡吗？
Aren't you asleep?
去睡觉吧，不然你会长黑眼圈的
Go to sleep or you'll get dark circles
你不是也醒着？
You're also awake, aren't you?
我躺着呢
I'm just lying down
你忘了吗？
Did you forget?
永远不要对夜晚撒谎
'Never lie to the night'
夜晚掌握着我们所有的秘密
'The night holds all our secrets'
- 我能告诉你一个秘密吗?-当然
- Can I tell you a secret? - Yes
我非常喜欢你
I like you a lot
真的吗？
Really?
以你的市场发誓？
Swear on your market?
阿贾德，我从我的线人那里得知
AK, I've found out from my sources
这个 SBI 的问题很严重
This SBI matter is serious
哈尔沙德可能有大麻烦了
Harshad could be in a big soup
总数是50亿卢比
And the amount is 500 crores
SBI那边怎么处理的？
And what is SBI doing about it?
他被给予了最后期限
He has been given a deadline to return all the money
“五亿卢比? ”
[Ajay] 'Five hundred crores?'
由于罢工，市场几天内不会开门
The market will not open for a few days because of the strike
‘是的’
[Tyagi] 'Yeah'
他不能在交易所拿钱
He can't get the money by trading there
因为他不能在那里交易
because he can't trade there
我想现在是掐死他的时候了
I think this is the time to strangle him
你觉得他会来找你吗？
You think he will come to you?
他必须来找我，他还能去找谁？
He has to Who else can he go to?
还有谁会给他50亿？
Who else will give him 500 crores?
没有人有能力购买他的股份
Nobody has the capacity to buy his holdings
他得把股票都卖给我们
He'll have to sell them all to us
按我们报的价格
And at the price that we quote
他要求再宽限一个星期
He asked for one more week
他得到了
and he got it
现在怎么办？
Now what?
你知道我们现在是什么角色吗？
Do you know what we are being made to look like?
该死的傻瓜，我们现在怎么办？
Bloody fools What do we do now?
我们应该正式报警，先生
We should file an official police complaint, sir
闭嘴
Shut up, Khemani
我去找哈沙德谈
I will talk to Harshad
你只是在浪费时间
You're just wasting time
SEBI 和经纪人之间不会有任何和解
There won't be any settlement between SEBI and the brokers
这次罢工还将持续几天
This strike will go on for a few days more
听着
Look
停手并不意味着你已经放弃
Stopping doesn't mean you've given up
SBI 的解决方案就在你们面前
The solution for SBI is right in front of you
你有这么多的股份，卖掉它们，解决问题吧
You have so many holdings Sell them and get rid of the problem
- 很简单-普拉纳夫说得对
-[Pranav] 'It's simple' - Pranav is right
戈伊波利亚一直威胁要告诉印度储备银行
That Goiporia has been continuously threatening to tell RBI
他连嘴都不肯开
He won't even open his mouth
如果他这么做了，SBI 也会陷入困境
If he does, SBI will also be in a soup
我们哪还有精力关心 SBI 发生了什么?
[Ashwin] 'What do we care what happens to SBI?'
我们陷得越深，麻烦就越大
The further we get caught up in this, the more trouble we'll be in
你知道吗？
You know what?
我会和八木那边谈的
I will talk to Tyagu
只需几句美言
A bit of spit and polish
他会给你一个公平的交易
And, he'll give you a fair deal
他不会给一个公平的交易，他会给一个该死的交易
He won't give a fair deal, he'll give a f**ked deal
- 我不会去花旗银行的-我们去找别人吧
- I will never go to Citibank - Let's go to someone else
SBI 资本市场如何？
How about SBI Capital Markets?
我们把股份卖给他们，与 SBI 结清我们的头寸
Let's sell our holdings to them and square off our position with SBI
- 你说呢?-你说得对
- What do you say? - You're right
怎么对? 卖掉所有东西？
What's right about this? Sell everything?
那么资本利得税呢？
And what about the capital gains tax?
税务局已经盯上我们了
The IT department is already up our noses
我不会让他们从我身上榨取一分钱
I won't let them make a penny out of me
忘记硬币
Forget pennies
我们说的可是50亿你明白吗？
We're talking about 500 crores Do you even understand?
-晚上好-晚上好
- Hari Om, Swami ji -[Swami] 'Hari Om'
你让我打电话给你
You had asked me to call
我们讨论过你的问题
We have debated your problem
别担心
Don't worry
“你的问题会解决的”
[Swami] 'Your work will be done'
-怎么解决?-国家住房银行
- But, how? - National Housing Bank
你的解决办法就在那里
[swami] 'Your solution lies there'
国家住房银行?
National Housing Bank?
你知道主席是谁吗？
Do you know who the chairman is?
菲尔瓦尼，我知道
Pherwani I know
费尔瓦尼和我相处得不好，阁下
Pherwani and I don't get along at all, Swami ji
他在 UTI 的时候，一分钱也没给我
When he was in UTI, he didn't give me a penny's business
他一听到我的名字就跑掉了
He runs away on hearing my name
“这只是意见分歧”
[Swami] 'It's a difference of opinions'
我们会消除你们的分歧
'We'll clear out your differences'
晚安，阁下
Hari Om, Swami ji
晚安
[Swami] 'Hari Om'
Hari Om
我就知道 这就是我能看到真正牛市的地方
I knew this is where I would see the real bull-run
我能安静的跑步吗？
Can I finish my run?
每个人都在奔跑
Everyone is running
重要的是 他们想去哪里？
What's important is where do they want to reach?
梅塔先生
Mr Mehta
我可以先跑完吗? 我们晚些时候见面好吗？
Can I jog? We'll meet sometime later?
我认为你只有到达德里才会停下来
I think your run will only stop once you have reached Delhi
那天我在那儿
I was there, the other day
新德里
Teen Murti Bhavan, Delhi
我和中央的人聊了一会儿
I had a chat with Swami ji
你一定也跟他聊了吧？
You also must have?
国会议员
Member of Parliament MP
听起来不错，先生
Sounds good, sir
你尽可以仔细看看，已经支付了最高限额
Look as closely as you want Maximum payment has been made
现在只剩下六亿卢比了，你很快也会得到的
Only six crores remain, and you'll get that soon too
高兴吗？
Happy?
你无缘无故地恐慌
[Harshad] 'You panic for no reason'
我建议去野餐
I suggest, go on a picnic
让可怜的西塔拉曼也去度假吧
Let poor Sitaraman also take a vacation
“生意对我来说就是宗教，先生”
[Harshad] 'Business is religion to me, sir'
这个宗教的上帝是信任
'And the God of this religion is Trust'
一个好朋友曾经告诉我
A close friend once told me
”世界上最贵的东西就是信任”
"the most expensive thing in the world is trust"
穷人买不起
Cheap people can't afford it
为什么这么久才把茶端来？
What took so long in bringing the tea?
请吧，先生
Please have, sir
今天天气很好，对吧？
It is sweet today, right?
我让你把司机带来
I had asked you to bring the driver along
但你就不带
But no
你要按多少下喇叭？
How much will you honk?
我是带你去兜风，不是带出来坐车
I am taking you for a drive, not the driver
那就别按喇叭了
Then, stop honking
这就是现在的情况
That's how it is these days
我的脑子里总是有声音
There's always a noise in my head
我甚至不能和你安静地呆上几个小时
I can't even spend a few hours with you in peace
谢天谢地，你们股市的噪音
Thankfully, the noise of your share market
我们这里听不到
doesn't reach our ears
很好
That's good
你爸爸是对的
Your dad is right
我一直忙于工作，忘记了家庭生活的滋味
I've been so busy with my work, I've forgotten the taste of family life
你一直在听从我爸爸的建议，是吗？
You've been taking advice from my dad, haven't you?
带我去看戏不是他的主意吗？
Wasn't it his idea, to take me out for a play?
是的
Yes
所以你才要带我去
That's why you are taking me
我不想去
I don't want to go
事实上，我根本不需要看这部戏
Actually, I don't need to watch this play at all
戏剧女王就坐在我旁边
The biggest drama queen is sitting right beside me
反正我们也看不到
We won't be able to see it, anyway
逾期不得入场
Late entry is not allowed
我们不可能准时到达
And we are not going to make it on time
在哈沙德统治时期，一切都是可能的，你明白吗？
Everything is allowed in Harshad's reign Do you get it?
哈沙德的统治，没错！
Harshad's rule, right!
我们一定能进场的
We'll make it
- 一旦那辆车开动……-是的，再按几下喇叭
- Once that car moves - Yes, honk some more
- 先生! 先生，有电话-[观众大笑]
- 'Sir! Sir, there's a call' -[audience laughing]
“是谁? ”
'Who is it?'
- “爸爸”-“那么，和他谈谈”
- 'Dad' - 'So Talk to him'
不是我爸爸是你老婆的爸爸
'Not my dad Your wife's dad'
“你是说，巴布拉尔? 我的岳父? ”
'You mean, Babulal? My father-in-law?'
- 是的-别提他的名字！
- Yes - Don't take his name!
他给我的股份一点用都没有，没有回报，也没有红利
'What a useless share he has handed me No return, and no dividend'
就像我父亲通过投资像你这样的人而获利一样
'Like my father has made a profit By investing in someone like you'
可怜的人，他听错了，你的名字是 Bakul
'Poor man He misheard Your name is Bakul'
“他听到了大牛的话” ，这就是他犯错误的原因
'He heard Big Bull' That's why he made a mistake'
“你应该庆幸我不是大牛”
'You should be grateful that I am not the Big Bull'
或者像他一样，我会欺骗你的父亲，然后逃跑
'Or like him, I would have swindled your father and run away'
他还在打电话，我该怎么跟他说
'He's still on the phone What do I tell him?'
告诉 Babulal，市场正处于高位
'Tell that Babulal, That the market is on a high'
但是他的份额已经跌到了地上
'But his share has dropped to the ground'
“现在就挂电话! ”
'Hang up now!'
但他从哪里得到资金偿还债务呢？
'But where did he get the funds to repay?'
交易所在罢工
The market is on strike
如果他在别的地方拿到这么大一笔钱，一定会有人知道的
Someone would have known if he had done such a big deal elsewhere
我的线人正在调查
My sources are trying to find out
但是他还没有归还所有的钱
But he hasn't returned all the money yet
SBI 对这件事保持沉默
SBI is silent on the matter
显然是因为他还钱了
Obviously, because he's returning the money
这件事很快就会被忘记
The matter will be forgotten soon
但是如果这个消息被泄露了怎么办？
But what if this news were to get leaked?
他从 SBI 那里拿走了50亿卢比，没有任何 br 或 SGL
He's taken 500 crore rupees from SBI without any BRs or SGL
现在他要还钱，因为他已经暴露了
And now, he's returning the money because he's been exposed
这不是一件小事
It's not a small matter, AK
他骗了 SBI，这是个骗局
He has conned SBI It's a fraud
迟早，哈萨德将不得不面对现实
And sooner or later, Harshad will have to face the music
他甚至可能进监狱
He can even go behind bars
如果这个消息泄露出去
If this news gets leaked
整个市场都会动摇
the entire market will be shaken
是的
Yes
但是
But
谁去曝光这件事？
who will bell the cat?
谁会泄露出去？
Who will leak it?
我们在 SBI 有朋友吗
'Do we have any friends at SBI?'
我是贝拉里
Bellary